{
  "211": {
    "question_text": "Consider two transactions and which are executed in the schedule below: read(D) write(D) read(A) write(A) commit read(B) write(B) abort If the database server goes down right after executing commit from and no changes have been written to disk yet, what will a transaction manager do after the database server is up later?",
    "choices": [
      "Redo the operations that have been committed, i.e., write(D) from T2 and write(A) from T1",
      "Undo the operations that have been committed, i.e., write(D) from T2 and write(A) from T1",
      "Redo the operations that have been committed, i.e., write(D) from T2",
      "Undo the operations that have been committed, i.e., write(D) from T2"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Redo the operations that have been committed, i.e., write(D) from T2"
  },
  "210": {
    "question_text": "Consider two transactions and which are executed in the schedule below: read(D) write(D) read(A) write(A) commit read(B) write(B) abort After executing abort from , what will the transaction manager do?",
    "choices": [
      "Redo the operations that have not been committed, i.e., write(A) and write(B) from T1",
      "Undo the operations that have not been committed, i.e., write(A) and write(B) from T1",
      "Redo the operations that have not been committed, i.e., write(B) from T1",
      "Undo the operations that have not been committed, i.e., write(B) from T1"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Undo the operations that have not been committed, i.e., write(A) and write(B) from T1"
  },
  "209": {
    "question_text": "Consider the following two transactions and , which transfer money between different accounts. If the transaction isolation level is \u00e2\u0080\u009cread uncommitted\u00e2\u0080\u009d, which of the following schedules is not serializable? * { box-sizing: border-box; } .column { float: left; width: 20%; padding:9px; height: 400px; } .row:after { content: \"\"; display: table; clear: both; } 1 read(A) A=A-10 write(A) read(B) B=B+10 write(B) commit read(B) B=B-20 write(B) read(D) D=D+20 write(D) commit 2 read(A) read(B) A=A-10 B=B-20 write(A) write(B) read(B) read(D) B=B+10 write(B) commit D=D+20 write(D) commit 3 read(A) A=A-10 read(B) write(A) read(B) B=B-20 write(B) B=B+10 read(D) write(B) commit D=D+20 write(D) commit",
    "choices": [
      "None of 1, 2 and 3",
      "Schedule 1",
      "Schedule 2",
      "Schedule 3"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Schedule 3"
  },
  "208": {
    "question_text": "Consider two transactions and , and the following schedules in which A and B are two records. Which of the following schedules can result in a deadlock? * { box-sizing: border-box; } .column { float: left; width: 20%; padding: 10px; height: 300px; } .row:after { content: \"\"; display: table; clear: both; } 1 read(A) write(A) read(A) write(A) commit commit 2 read(A) read(B) write(A) write(B) commit commit 3 read(A) write(B) read(A) write(B) commit commit 4 read(A) read(A) write(A) write(B) commit commit",
    "choices": [
      "Schedule 1and Schedule 2",
      "Schedule 2 and Schedule 3",
      "Schedule 3 and Schedule 4",
      "Schedule 1 and Schedule 4",
      "Schedule 2 and Schedule 4"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Schedule 2 and Schedule 4"
  },
  "206": {
    "question_text": "Consider the table Worker(name, payrate, hours) with name as the primary key and the following transaction: Begin transaction; update Worker set hours = 20 where name = \u00e2\u0080\u0098Tom'; update Worker set payrate = 1.5*payrate where name = \u00e2\u0080\u0098Tom'; Commit; Rollback; What does Rollback do?",
    "choices": [
      "Undo the changes before commit",
      "Clear all changes",
      "Redo the changes before commit",
      "Nothing"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Nothing"
  },
  "207": {
    "question_text": "Consider the table Worker(name, payrate, hours) with name as the primary key and the following two concurrent transactions: : Begin Transaction; update Worker set payrate = 1.2*payrate where name = \u00e2\u0080\u0098Tom'; update Worker set payrate = 1.5*payrate where name = \u00e2\u0080\u0098Tom'; Commit; : Begin Transaction; update Worker set payrate = payrate+20 where name = \u00e2\u0080\u0098Tom'; update Worker set payrate = payrate+10 where name = \u00e2\u0080\u0098Tom'; Commit; Assume Tom\u00e2\u0080\u0099s pay rate is 20 before the transactions and begin. If the transaction isolation level is \u00e2\u0080\u009cread uncommitted\u00e2\u0080\u009d, what are the possible values for Tom\u00e2\u0080\u0099s pay rate after executing these two transactions?",
    "choices": [
      "66, 81, 82 and 90",
      "66, 76, 81, 82, 87, and 90",
      "66, 78, 81, 82, 88, and 90",
      "66 and 90",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "66, 76, 81, 82, 87, and 90"
  },
  "205": {
    "question_text": "Consider the table Worker(name, payrate, hours) with name as the primary key and the following two concurrent transactions: : Begin Transaction; update Worker set payrate = 1.2*payrate where name = \u00e2\u0080\u0098Tom'; update Worker set payrate = 1.5*payrate where name = \u00e2\u0080\u0098Tom'; Commit; : Begin Transaction; update Worker set payrate = payrate+20 where name = \u00e2\u0080\u0098Tom'; update Worker set payrate = payrate+10 where name = \u00e2\u0080\u0098Tom'; Commit; Assume Tom\u00e2\u0080\u0099s pay rate is 20 before the transactions and begin. If the transaction isolation level is \u00e2\u0080\u009cread committed\u00e2\u0080\u009d, what are the possible values for Tom\u00e2\u0080\u0099s pay rate after executing these two transactions?",
    "choices": [
      "66 and 82",
      "81 and 90",
      "66 and 90",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "66 and 90"
  },
  "204": {
    "question_text": "Consider the table Worker(name, payrate, hours) with name as the primary key and the following two concurrent transactions: : Begin Transaction; update Worker set payrate = 1.2*payrate where name = \u00e2\u0080\u0098Tom'; update Worker set payrate = 1.5*payrate where name = \u00e2\u0080\u0098Tom'; Commit; : Begin Transaction; update Worker set payrate = payrate+20 where name = \u00e2\u0080\u0098Tom'; update Worker set payrate = payrate+10 where name = \u00e2\u0080\u0098Tom'; Commit; Assume Tom\u00e2\u0080\u0099s pay rate is 20 before the transactions and begin. If the transaction isolation level is \u00e2\u0080\u009cserializable\u00e2\u0080\u009d, what are the possible values for Tom's pay rate after executing these two transactions?",
    "choices": [
      "66 and 82",
      "81 and 90",
      "66 and 90",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "66 and 90"
  },
  "203": {
    "question_text": "Consider two transactions and , and the following schedule in which A and B are two records. read(A) read(A) write(A) read(B) write(A) commit commit Which of the following problems may occur in this schedule?",
    "choices": [
      "Lost update",
      "Dirty read",
      "Unrepeatable read",
      "Phantom read"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Lost update"
  },
  "202": {
    "question_text": "Consider two transactions and , and the following schedule in which A and B are two records. read(B) read(A) write(A) read(A) read(B) write(B) commit Abort Which of the following problems may occur in this schedule?",
    "choices": [
      "Lost update",
      "Phantom read",
      "Dirty read",
      "Unrepeatable read"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Unrepeatable read"
  },
  "201": {
    "question_text": "Consider two transactions and , and the following schedule in which A and B are two records. read(A) write(A) read(A) write(A) read(B) commit abort Which of the following problems may occur in this schedule?",
    "choices": [
      "Lost update",
      "Dirty read",
      "Unrepeatable read",
      "Phantom read"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Dirty read"
  },
  "200": {
    "question_text": "Which properties are ensured by the transaction manager through logging?",
    "choices": [
      "Atomicity and integrity",
      "Atomicity and durability",
      "Atomicity and isolation",
      "Durability and isolation"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Atomicity and durability"
  },
  "199": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following are the advantages of concurrent transactions?",
    "choices": [
      "Increase throughput",
      "Reduce average response time",
      "Increase utilisation",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "All of the above"
  },
  "198": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following problems occurs when a transaction re-reads a table and finds new rows that were inserted into a table by other transactions since its prior read?",
    "choices": [
      "Unrepeatable read",
      "Phantom read",
      "Dirty read",
      "Lost update"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Phantom read"
  },
  "197": {
    "question_text": "For the two-phase locking protocol, which of the following statements is true?",
    "choices": [
      "Once a transaction has released a lock, this transaction can not acquire any more locks",
      "A transaction can release all its locks when this transaction commits",
      "A transaction can acquire all the locks which it needs when this transaction begins",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "All of the above"
  },
  "196": {
    "question_text": "What operation(s) can a transaction perform if this transaction acquires an exclusive lock?",
    "choices": [
      "Read",
      "Write",
      "Read and write",
      "Update"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Read and write"
  },
  "195": {
    "question_text": "What is the correctness criterion for concurrent transactions?",
    "choices": [
      "Consistency",
      "Serializability",
      "Atomicity",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Serializability"
  },
  "194": {
    "question_text": "Which transaction isolation level does not allow dirty reads but does allow unrepeatable reads and phantom reads?",
    "choices": [
      "Read committed",
      "Read uncommitted",
      "Serializable",
      "Repeatable read"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Read committed"
  },
  "193": {
    "question_text": "Given two transactions and , which of the following statements is true?",
    "choices": [
      "T1 and T2 produce correct results if T1 is executed after T2 commits",
      "T1 and T2 produce correct results if T1 and T2 are executed concurrently but do not access any common data items",
      "All of the above",
      "A schedule of T1 and T2 can be serialized if T1 and T2 are executed under the two phase locking protocol"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "All of the above"
  },
  "192": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following is responsible for ensuring the property isolation of database transactions?",
    "choices": [
      "Recover manager",
      "Concurrency control",
      "Storage manager",
      "File manager"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Concurrency control"
  },
  "191": {
    "question_text": "An internet banking system requires a user to enter their password, then the system sends an SMS to the user\u00e2\u0080\u0099s registered mobile phone, containing another sequence of characters, and the user must enter this as well. Which of the following terms describes this example of authentication?",
    "choices": [
      "Authentication by what you have",
      "Authentication by what you know",
      "Authentication by what you are",
      "Two-factor authentication"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Two-factor authentication"
  },
  "190": {
    "question_text": "What is a covert channel?",
    "choices": [
      "A method that is used to secretly pass information and not normally used for communication",
      "A method that is used to transmit secret or top secret data",
      "A trusted channel that is used for communication",
      "Any channel that crosses the security perimeter"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "A method that is used to secretly pass information and not normally used for communication"
  },
  "189": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following is not true regarding Trojan horse attacks?",
    "choices": [
      "A Trojan is a small malicious program that runs hidden on the infected system.",
      "A Trojan is created with the intent and it can infect the system by misleading a user.",
      "A Trojan works in the background and steals sensitive data.",
      "A Trojan can self-replicate, as a virus does."
    ],
    "correct_answer": "A Trojan can self-replicate, as a virus does."
  },
  "188": {
    "question_text": "Which Bell-LaPadula rule prevents lower-level subjects from retrieving information from objects with a higher security level?",
    "choices": [
      "Write down rule",
      "Write up rule",
      "Read down rule",
      "Read up rule"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Read down rule"
  },
  "187": {
    "question_text": "What is the objective of database security which says that people shouldn\u00e2\u0080\u0099t change data unless they are supposed to change it, and they also shouldn\u00e2\u0080\u0099t change data in ways different from how they are supposed to change it.",
    "choices": [
      "Confidentiality",
      "Availability",
      "Integrity",
      "Accountability"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Integrity"
  },
  "186": {
    "question_text": "Assuming that Linda is the owner of the relation Event, after completing the following three actions, which of the following statements is correct? Step | By | Action 1 | Linda| GRANT select TO Amy, Peter ON Event WITH GRANT OPTION; 2 |Amy| GRANT select TO Peter ON Event; 3 |Linda| REVOKE select ON Event FROM Amy CASCADE;",
    "choices": [
      "Both Amy and Peter have the select privilege on Event",
      "Amy has the select privilege on Event, but Peter does not have this privilege",
      "Peter has the select privilege on Event, but Amy does not have this privilege",
      "None of Amy and Peter have the select privilege on Event"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Peter has the select privilege on Event, but Amy does not have this privilege"
  },
  "185": {
    "question_text": "Assuming that Linda is the owner of the relation Event, after completing the following three actions, which of the following statements is correct? Step | By | Action 1 | Linda| GRANT select TO Amy ON Event WITH GRANT OPTION; 2 |Amy| GRANT select TO Peter ON Event; 3 |Linda| REVOKE GRANT OPTION FOR select ON Event FROM Amy CASCADE;",
    "choices": [
      "Both Amy and Peter have the select privilege on Event",
      "Amy has the select privilege on Event, but Peter does not have this privilege",
      "Peter has the select privilege on Event, but Amy does not have this privilege",
      "None of Amy and Peter have the select privilege on Event"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Amy has the select privilege on Event, but Peter does not have this privilege"
  },
  "184": {
    "question_text": "What is an authentication method?",
    "choices": [
      "A method of restricting user access to a database system",
      "A method of restricting user access to data in a database system",
      "A method of restricting operations on data stored in a database system",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "A method of restricting user access to a database system"
  },
  "183": {
    "question_text": "You work as a database administrator at ToyWorld. They manage database security using a Role Based Access Control (RBAC) model. There are three types of resources, including files, printers, and mailboxes, and four departments with distinct functions: Sales, Marketing, Management, and Production in ToyWorld. Each department needs access to different resources. Each user has a workstation. Which roles should you create to support this RBAC model?",
    "choices": [
      "File, printer, and mailbox roles.",
      "Sales, marketing, management, and production roles.",
      "User and workstation roles.",
      "Resource and department roles."
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Sales, marketing, management, and production roles."
  },
  "182": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following can potentially cause a SQL injection attack?",
    "choices": [
      "var City; City = Request.form (\"City\"); var SQL = \"select * from OrdersTable where City = '\" + City + \"'\";",
      "var SQL = \"select * from OrdersTable where City = \u00e2\u0080\u0098Canberra\u00e2\u0080\u0099\";",
      "var City; City =\u00e2\u0080\u0098Canberra\u00e2\u0080\u0099; var SQL = \"select * from OrdersTable where City = '\" + City + \u00e2\u0080\u009c'\";",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "var City; City = Request.form (\"City\"); var SQL = \"select * from OrdersTable where City = '\" + City + \"'\";"
  },
  "173": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following are used to make access decisions in Mandatory Access Control (MAC)?",
    "choices": [
      "Access control list and Ownership",
      "Group membership and Role",
      "User security clearance and Data classification"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "User security clearance and Data classification"
  },
  "181": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following is an inherent flaw in Discretionary Access Control (DAC)?",
    "choices": [
      "DAC relies only on the identity of a user, leaving room for Trojan Horse attacks.",
      "DAC relies on certificates of a user, leaving room for attackers to use those certificates.",
      "DAC does not rely on the identity of a user, leaving room for Trojan Horse attacks.",
      "DAC does not regulate the role of a user, leaving room for Trojan Horse attacks."
    ],
    "correct_answer": "DAC relies only on the identity of a user, leaving room for Trojan Horse attacks."
  },
  "180": {
    "question_text": "For Discretionary Access Control (DAC), which of the following statements is true?",
    "choices": [
      "Objects that do not have an owner cannot be modified.",
      "The database administrator is an owner of each object.",
      "For each object, the database administrator can grant privileges to other users at their own discretion.",
      "Each object has an owner who has full control on managing the privileges to the object."
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Each object has an owner who has full control on managing the privileges to the object."
  },
  "179": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following is true regarding views?",
    "choices": [
      "A user who creates a view can always receive the select and update privileges on that view.",
      "A user who creates a view can always receive the update privilege on that view if the user has the update privilege on the underlying tables/views used to define the view.",
      "A user who creates a view does not necessarily receive all privileges on that view.",
      "A user who creates a view receives all privileges on that view."
    ],
    "correct_answer": "A user who creates a view does not necessarily receive all privileges on that view."
  },
  "178": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following is used to avoid cascading of revoking privileges?",
    "choices": [
      "GRANT select ON salary TO Tom no cascade;",
      "REVOKE select ON salary FROM Tom restrict;",
      "GRANT select ON salary TO Tom no restrict;",
      "REVOKE select ON salary FROM Tom cascade;"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "REVOKE select ON salary FROM Tom restrict;"
  },
  "171": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following statements are not correct?",
    "choices": [
      "SQL injection may occur when an input is used in the construction of an SQL query without being adequately constrained or sanitized",
      "SQL injection allows an attacker to access a SQL database and execute SQL commands under the privileges of a user who connects to the database",
      "SQL injection can be prevented by removing the privileges of a user who connects to the database",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "SQL injection can be prevented by removing the privileges of a user who connects to the database"
  },
  "177": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following is a characteristic of Mandatory Access Control (MAC)?",
    "choices": [
      "Use different levels of security to classify users and data.",
      "Allow owners of objects to determine who has access to their objects",
      "Control a list of authorized users using the GRANT and REVOKE commands",
      "Manage access control lists by assigning roles to users"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Use different levels of security to classify users and data."
  },
  "176": {
    "question_text": "If we wish to grant a privilege to a user and also allow the user to pass the privilege on to other users, which of the following should we append to the appropriate grant command?",
    "choices": [
      "With grant privilege",
      "Allow grant privilege",
      "Allow grant option",
      "With grant option"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "With grant option"
  },
  "175": {
    "question_text": "Which technology is not used to enforce confidentiality of database security?",
    "choices": [
      "Data encryption",
      "Access controls",
      "Auditing",
      "Authentication"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Auditing"
  },
  "174": {
    "question_text": "In SQL, which of the following cannot be granted privileges using the GRANT command?",
    "choices": [
      "A specified attribute",
      "A specified tuple",
      "An entire relation",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "A specified tuple"
  },
  "170": {
    "question_text": "Consider the following database schema: Movie(title, production year, country, run time, major genre) primary key : {title, production year} Person(id, first name, last name, year born) primary key : {id} Director(id, title, production year) primary key : {title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Writer(id, title, production year, credits) primary key : {id, title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Which of the following RAs output the titles and production years of the movies which were written by writers born after 1980? A: 1980}(Person))) }\" border=\"0\"/> B: 1980}(Person))) }\" border=\"0\"/>",
    "choices": [
      "only A",
      "only B",
      "both A and B",
      "neither A nor B"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "only A"
  },
  "169": {
    "question_text": "Consider the following database schema: Movie(title, production year, country, run time, major genre) primary key : {title, production year} Person(id, first name, last name, year born) primary key : {id} Director(id, title, production year) primary key : {title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Writer(id, title, production year, credits) primary key : {id, title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Which of the following RAs output the titles and production years of the movies which were written by writers born after 1980? A: 1980}(Person)))) }\" border=\"0\"/> B: 1980}(Person))) }\" border=\"0\"/>",
    "choices": [
      "only A",
      "only B",
      "both A and B",
      "neither A nor B"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "both A and B"
  },
  "168": {
    "question_text": "Consider the following database schema: Movie(title, production year, country, run time, major genre) primary key : {title, production year} Person(id, first name, last name, year born) primary key : {id} Director(id, title, production year) primary key : {title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Writer(id, title, production year, credits) primary key : {id, title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Which of the following RAs output the ids of the directors who have directed any comedy or action movies? A: B:",
    "choices": [
      "only A",
      "only B",
      "both A and B",
      "neither A nor B"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "both A and B"
  },
  "167": {
    "question_text": "Consider the following database schema: Movie(title, production year, country, run time, major genre) primary key : {title, production year} Person(id, first name, last name, year born) primary key : {id} Director(id, title, production year) primary key : {title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Writer(id, title, production year, credits) primary key : {id, title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Which of the following RAs will output the ids of the directors who have directed any comedy or action movies? A: B:",
    "choices": [
      "only A",
      "only B",
      "both A and B",
      "neither A nor B"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "both A and B"
  },
  "166": {
    "question_text": "Consider the following database schema: Movie(title, production year, country, run time, major genre) primary key : {title, production year} Person(id, first name, last name, year born) primary key : {id} Director(id, title, production year) primary key : {title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Writer(id, title, production year, credits) primary key : {id, title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Which of the following RAs will give you the ids of the directors who have directed both comedy movies and action movies? A: B:",
    "choices": [
      "only A",
      "only B",
      "both A and B",
      "neither A nor B"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "neither A nor B"
  },
  "165": {
    "question_text": "Consider the following database schema: Movie(title, production year, country, run time, major genre) primary key : {title, production year} Person(id, first name, last name, year born) primary key : {id} Director(id, title, production year) primary key : {title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Writer(id, title, production year, credits) primary key : {id, title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Which of the following RAs will give you the ids of the directors who have directed both comedy movies and action movies? A: B:",
    "choices": [
      "only A",
      "only B",
      "both A and B",
      "neither A nor B"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "only B"
  },
  "164": {
    "question_text": "Consider the following database schema: Movie(title, production year, country, run time, major genre) primary key : {title, production year} Person(id, first name, last name, year born) primary key : {id} Director(id, title, production year) primary key : {title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Writer(id, title, production year, credits) primary key : {id, title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Which of the following RAs will output the ids of the writers who have written movies produced in year 2000 but not in year 2010? A: B:",
    "choices": [
      "only A",
      "only B",
      "both A and B",
      "neither A nor B"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "neither A nor B"
  },
  "163": {
    "question_text": "Consider the following database schema: Movie(title, production year, country, run time, major genre) primary key : {title, production year} Person(id, first name, last name, year born) primary key : {id} Director(id, title, production year) primary key : {title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Writer(id, title, production year, credits) primary key : {id, title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Which of the following RAs will output the first and last names of the directors who have never written any movies? A: B:",
    "choices": [
      "only A",
      "only B",
      "both A and B",
      "neither A nor B"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "only B"
  },
  "162": {
    "question_text": "Consider the following database schema: Movie(title, production year, country, run time, major genre) primary key : {title, production year} Person(id, first name, last name, year born) primary key : {id} Director(id, title, production year) primary key : {title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Writer(id, title, production year, credits) primary key : {id, title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Which of the following RAs will output the first and last names of the directors who have never written any movies? A: B:",
    "choices": [
      "only A",
      "only B",
      "both A and B",
      "neither A nor B"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "neither A nor B"
  },
  "161": {
    "question_text": "Consider the following database schema: Movie(title, production year, country, run time, major genre) primary key : {title, production year} Person(id, first name, last name, year born) primary key : {id} Director(id, title, production year) primary key : {title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Writer(id, title, production year, credits) primary key : {id, title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Which of the following RAs will output the first and last names of the writers who were born in 1970 and have written movies produced in 2010? A: B:",
    "choices": [
      "only A",
      "only B",
      "both A and B",
      "neither A nor B"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "both A and B"
  },
  "160": {
    "question_text": "Consider the following database schema: Movie(title, production year, country, run time, major genre) primary key : {title, production year} Person(id, first name, last name, year born) primary key : {id} Director(id, title, production year) primary key : {title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Writer(id, title, production year, credits) primary key : {id, title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Which of the following RAs will output the first and last names of the directors who have directed movies produced in USA? A: B:",
    "choices": [
      "only B",
      "neither A nor B",
      "both A and B",
      " only A"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "both A and B"
  },
  "159": {
    "question_text": "Consider the following database schema: Movie(title, production year, country, run time, major genre) primary key : {title, production year} Person(id, first name, last name, year born) primary key : {id} Director(id, title, production year) primary key : {title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Writer(id, title, production year, credits) primary key : {id, title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Are the following two RA expressions equivalent?",
    "choices": [
      "Yes",
      "No"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Yes"
  },
  "158": {
    "question_text": "Consider the following database schema: Movie(title, production year, country, run time, major genre) primary key : {title, production year} Person(id, first name, last name, year born) primary key : {id} Director(id, title, production year) primary key : {title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Writer(id, title, production year, credits) primary key : {id, title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Are the following two RA expressions equivalent?",
    "choices": [
      "Yes",
      "No"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "No"
  },
  "157": {
    "question_text": "Consider the following database schema: Movie(title, production year, country, run time, major genre) primary key : {title, production year} Person(id, first name, last name, year born) primary key : {id} Director(id, title, production year) primary key : {title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Writer(id, title, production year, credits) primary key : {id, title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Are the following two RA expressions equivalent?",
    "choices": [
      "Yes",
      "No"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "No"
  },
  "156": {
    "question_text": "Consider the following database schema: Movie(title, production year, country, run time, major genre) primary key : {title, production year} Person(id, first name, last name, year born) primary key : {id} Director(id, title, production year) primary key : {title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Writer(id, title, production year, credits) primary key : {id, title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Are the following two RA expressions equivalent?",
    "choices": [
      "Yes",
      "No"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "No"
  },
  "155": {
    "question_text": "Consider the following database schema: Movie(title, production year, country, run time, major genre) primary key : {title, production year} Person(id, first name, last name, year born) primary key : {id} Director(id, title, production year) primary key : {title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Writer(id, title, production year, credits) primary key : {id, title, production year} foreign keys : [title, production year] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Movie[title, production year], [id] \u00e2\u008a\u0086 Person[id] Are the following two RA expressions equivalent?",
    "choices": [
      "Yes",
      "No"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Yes"
  },
  "172": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following relational algebra expression?",
    "choices": [
      "16",
      "8",
      "5",
      "4"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "4"
  },
  "154": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following relational algebra expression?",
    "choices": [
      "28",
      "17",
      "12",
      "7"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "17"
  },
  "153": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following relational algebra expression?",
    "choices": [
      "16",
      "8",
      "4",
      "0"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "16"
  },
  "141": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following relational algebra expression?",
    "choices": [
      "28",
      "21",
      "12",
      "7"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "21"
  },
  "152": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following relational algebra expression?",
    "choices": [
      "12",
      "9",
      "7",
      "3"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "3"
  },
  "151": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following relational algebra expression?",
    "choices": [
      "16",
      "12",
      "8",
      "4"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "4"
  },
  "150": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following relational algebra expression?",
    "choices": [
      "28",
      "12",
      "7",
      "4"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "7"
  },
  "149": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following relational algebra expression?",
    "choices": [
      "28",
      "12",
      "7",
      "4"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "7"
  },
  "148": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following relational algebra expression?",
    "choices": [
      "28",
      "12",
      "7",
      "4"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "12"
  },
  "147": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following relational algebra expression?",
    "choices": [
      "28",
      "12",
      "7",
      "4"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "28"
  },
  "146": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following relational algebra expression?",
    "choices": [
      "4",
      "3",
      "2",
      "1"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "2"
  },
  "145": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following relational algebra expression?",
    "choices": [
      "4",
      "3",
      "2",
      "1"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "1"
  },
  "144": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following relational algebra expression?",
    "choices": [
      "6",
      "5",
      "4",
      "3"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "4"
  },
  "143": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following relational algebra expression?",
    "choices": [
      "4",
      "3",
      "2",
      "1"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "3"
  },
  "140": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following relational algebra expression?",
    "choices": [
      "4",
      "3",
      "2",
      "1"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "3"
  },
  "142": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following relational algebra expression?",
    "choices": [
      "3",
      "2",
      "1",
      "0"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "2"
  },
  "139": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following relational algebra expression?",
    "choices": [
      "6",
      "4",
      "2",
      "0"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "4"
  },
  "138": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following is correct?",
    "choices": [
      "The BCNF decomposition is always unique for any R and \u00ce\u00a3.",
      "The 3NF decomposition is always unique for any R and \u00ce\u00a3.",
      "There exists an algorithm that can always generate a lossless and dependency-preserving decomposition into 3NF.",
      "There exists an algorithm that can always generate a lossless and dependency-preserving decomposition into BCNF."
    ],
    "correct_answer": "There exists an algorithm that can always generate a lossless and dependency-preserving decomposition into 3NF."
  },
  "137": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following is correct?",
    "choices": [
      "BCNF decomposition is always a dependency-preserving decomposition.",
      "3NF decomposition is always a dependency-preserving decomposition.",
      "BCNF decomposition cannot be a dependency-preserving decomposition.",
      "3NF decomposition cannot be a dependency-preserving decomposition."
    ],
    "correct_answer": "3NF decomposition is always a dependency-preserving decomposition."
  },
  "136": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following is correct?",
    "choices": [
      "If R is in BCNF, then R must be in 3NF.",
      "If R is in 3NF, then R must be in BCNF.",
      "If R is in BCNF, then R cannot be in 3NF.",
      "If R is in 3NF, then R cannot be in BCNF."
    ],
    "correct_answer": "If R is in BCNF, then R must be in 3NF."
  },
  "135": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following is correct about 3NF?",
    "choices": [
      "3NF is a a more restrictive normal form compared to BCNF.",
      "3NF can only minimise (not necessarily eliminate) redundancy.",
      "3NF eliminates redundancy. "
    ],
    "correct_answer": "3NF can only minimise (not necessarily eliminate) redundancy."
  },
  "134": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following is correct about BCNF?",
    "choices": [
      "BCNF is a a less restrictive normal form compared to 3NF.",
      "BCNF can only minimise (not necessarily eliminate) redundancy.",
      "BCNF eliminates redundancy. "
    ],
    "correct_answer": "BCNF eliminates redundancy. "
  },
  "133": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C,D}, \u00ce\u00a3={AB\u00e2\u0086\u0092 CD, C\u00e2\u0086\u0092 A}. Which of the following is correct?",
    "choices": [
      "R is in 3NF and R is in BCNF.",
      "R is in 3NF and R is not in BCNF.",
      "R is not in 3NF and R is not in BCNF.",
      "R is not in 3NF and R is in BCNF."
    ],
    "correct_answer": "R is in 3NF and R is not in BCNF."
  },
  "132": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C,D}, \u00ce\u00a3={AB\u00e2\u0086\u0092 CD, BC\u00e2\u0086\u0092 A}. Which of the following is correct?",
    "choices": [
      "R is in 3NF and R is in BCNF.",
      "R is in 3NF and R is not in BCNF.",
      "R is not in 3NF and R is not in BCNF.",
      "R is not in 3NF and R is in BCNF."
    ],
    "correct_answer": "R is in 3NF and R is in BCNF."
  },
  "131": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C}, \u00ce\u00a3={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, B\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C}. Which of the following is correct?",
    "choices": [
      "R is in 3NF and R is in BCNF.",
      "R is in 3NF and R is not in BCNF.",
      "R is not in 3NF and R is not in BCNF.",
      "R is not in 3NF and R is in BCNF."
    ],
    "correct_answer": "R is not in 3NF and R is not in BCNF."
  },
  "130": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C}, \u00ce\u00a3={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 BC, BC\u00e2\u0086\u0092 A}. Which of the following is correct?",
    "choices": [
      "R is in 3NF and R is in BCNF.",
      "R is in 3NF and R is not in BCNF.",
      "R is not in 3NF and R is not in BCNF.",
      "R is not in 3NF and R is in BCNF."
    ],
    "correct_answer": "R is in 3NF and R is in BCNF."
  },
  "129": {
    "question_text": "R={A, B, C} and \u00ce\u00a3 = {A\u00e2\u0086\u0092BC}. Which of the following is correct?",
    "choices": [
      "R is in 3NF and R is in BCNF.",
      "R is in 3NF and R is not in BCNF.",
      "R is not in 3NF and R is not in BCNF.",
      "R is not in 3NF and R is in BCNF."
    ],
    "correct_answer": "R is in 3NF and R is in BCNF."
  },
  "128": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following is correct?",
    "choices": [
      "A relation schema R is in BCNF if whenever a non-trivial FD X\u00e2\u0086\u0092 A holds in R, then A is a prime attribute.",
      "A relation schema R is in 3NF if whenever a non-trivial FD X\u00e2\u0086\u0092 A holds in R, then X is a superkey.",
      "A relation schema R is in BCNF if whenever a non-trivial FD X\u00e2\u0086\u0092 A holds in R, then X is a superkey.",
      "A relation schema R is in 3NF if whenever a non-trivial FD X\u00e2\u0086\u0092 A holds in R, then A is a prime attribute."
    ],
    "correct_answer": "A relation schema R is in BCNF if whenever a non-trivial FD X\u00e2\u0086\u0092 A holds in R, then X is a superkey."
  },
  "127": {
    "question_text": "R={A, B, C} and \u00ce\u00a3 = {A\u00e2\u0086\u0092B, B\u00e2\u0086\u0092C, A\u00e2\u0086\u0092C}. The decomposition of R into R1 = {A, B} and R2 = {B, C}",
    "choices": [
      "Does not fulfil the lossless join property but fulfils the dependency preserving property.",
      "Fulfils both lossless join and dependency preserving properties.",
      "Fulfils neither the lossless join property nor the dependency preserving property.",
      "Fulfils the lossless join property but does not fulfil the dependency preserving property."
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Fulfils both lossless join and dependency preserving properties."
  },
  "126": {
    "question_text": "R={A, B, C} and \u00ce\u00a3 = {A\u00e2\u0086\u0092B, B\u00e2\u0086\u0092C, A\u00e2\u0086\u0092C}. The decomposition of R into R1 = {A, B} and R2 = {A, C}",
    "choices": [
      "Does not fulfil the lossless join property but fulfils the dependency preserving property.",
      "Fulfils both lossless join and dependency preserving properties.",
      "Fulfils neither the lossless join property nor the dependency preserving property.",
      "Fulfils the lossless join property but does not fulfil the dependency preserving property."
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Fulfils the lossless join property but does not fulfil the dependency preserving property."
  },
  "125": {
    "question_text": "R={A, B, C} and \u00ce\u00a3 = {A\u00e2\u0086\u0092B, B\u00e2\u0086\u0092C}. The decomposition of R into R1 = {A, B} and R2 = {B, C}",
    "choices": [
      "Does not fulfil the lossless join property but fulfils the dependency preserving property.",
      "Fulfils both lossless join and dependency preserving properties.",
      "Fulfils neither the lossless join property nor the dependency preserving property.",
      "Fulfils the lossless join property but does not fulfil the dependency preserving property."
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Fulfils both lossless join and dependency preserving properties."
  },
  "124": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C, D}, \u00ce\u00a3={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092BCD, CD\u00e2\u0086\u0092AB}. Is the following statement true or false? A is the only CK of R.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "False"
  },
  "123": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C, D}, \u00ce\u00a3={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, B\u00e2\u0086\u0092 AD, CD\u00e2\u0086\u0092AB}. Is the following statement true or false? C must be part of each CK of R.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "True"
  },
  "122": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C}, \u00ce\u00a3={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, B\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C, C\u00e2\u0086\u0092A}. Is the following statement true or false? A, B and C are all prime attributes.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "True"
  },
  "121": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C}, \u00ce\u00a3={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, B\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C, C\u00e2\u0086\u0092A}. Is the following statement true or false? A is the only CK of R",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "False"
  },
  "120": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C}, \u00ce\u00a3={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, AB\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C}. Is the following statement true or false? A is the only CK of R",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "True"
  },
  "119": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C}, \u00ce\u00a3={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, AB\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C}. Is the following statement true or false? AB is a CK of R",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "False"
  },
  "118": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C}, \u00ce\u00a3={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, AB\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C}. Is the following statement true or false? A is a CK of R",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "True"
  },
  "117": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C}, \u00ce\u00a31={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, AB\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C} and \u00ce\u00a32={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C}. Is the following statement true or false? \u00ce\u00a32 is a minimal cover of \u00ce\u00a31",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "True"
  },
  "116": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C}, \u00ce\u00a31={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, AB\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C} and \u00ce\u00a32={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, B\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C}. Is the following statement true or false? \u00ce\u00a32 is a minimal cover of \u00ce\u00a31",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "False"
  },
  "115": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C}, \u00ce\u00a31={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, AB\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C} and \u00ce\u00a32={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C}. Is the following statement true or false? \u00ce\u00a31 and \u00ce\u00a32 are equivalent",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "True"
  },
  "114": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C}, \u00ce\u00a31={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, AB\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C} and \u00ce\u00a32={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, B\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C}. Is the following statement true or false? \u00ce\u00a31 and \u00ce\u00a32 are equivalent",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "False"
  },
  "113": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C}, \u00ce\u00a31={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, B\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C} and \u00ce\u00a32={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C, B\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C}. Is the following statement true or false? \u00ce\u00a32 \u00e2\u008a\u00a8 \u00ce\u00a31",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "False"
  },
  "112": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C}, \u00ce\u00a31={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, B\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C} and \u00ce\u00a32={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C, B\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C}. Is the following statement true or false? \u00ce\u00a31 \u00e2\u008a\u00a8 \u00ce\u00a32",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "True"
  },
  "111": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C}, \u00ce\u00a31={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, B\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C} and \u00ce\u00a32={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C, B\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C}. Is the following statement true or false? \u00ce\u00a31 and \u00ce\u00a32 are equivalent",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "False"
  },
  "110": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C,D} and \u00ce\u00a3={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, B\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C, D\u00e2\u0086\u0092ABC}. Is the following statement true or false? \u00ce\u00a3 \u00e2\u008a\u00a8 D\u00e2\u0086\u0092 AC",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "True"
  },
  "109": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C,D} and \u00ce\u00a3={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, B\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C, D\u00e2\u0086\u0092ABC}. Is the following statement true or false? D is a SK of R",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "True"
  },
  "108": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C,D} and \u00ce\u00a3={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, B\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C, D\u00e2\u0086\u0092ABC}. The closure of D is",
    "choices": [
      "A",
      "AB",
      "ABC",
      "ABCD"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "ABCD"
  },
  "107": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C,D} and \u00ce\u00a3={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, B\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C, D\u00e2\u0086\u0092ABC}. Is the following statement true or false? \u00ce\u00a3 \u00e2\u008a\u00a8 A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "True"
  },
  "106": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C,D} and \u00ce\u00a3={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, B\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C, D\u00e2\u0086\u0092ABC}. Is the following statement true or false? A is a SK of R",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "False"
  },
  "105": {
    "question_text": "R={A,B,C,D} and \u00ce\u00a3={A\u00e2\u0086\u0092 B, B\u00e2\u0086\u0092 C, D\u00e2\u0086\u0092ABC}. The closure of A is",
    "choices": [
      "A",
      "AB",
      "ABC",
      "ABCD"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "ABC"
  },
  "104": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following is a trival FD?",
    "choices": [
      "XY\u00e2\u0086\u0092XYZ",
      "X\u00e2\u0086\u0092YZ",
      "XYZ\u00e2\u0086\u0092Z",
      "YZ\u00e2\u0086\u0092X"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "XYZ\u00e2\u0086\u0092Z"
  },
  "103": {
    "question_text": "Consider a database that stores names, addresses and unique IDs of employees in a fitness centre. The employees are classified into three categories: trainers, administrators and technicians. Each trainer has one or more specialities, e.g., weight gain, weight loss, strength building, etc. An administrator can register new members and be reached through a landline phone number. Each member is identified by an email address. The fitness centre organises fitness classes for members. Each class has a name, a start date, an end date, and a daily time slot. No two fitness classes have the same daily time slot, and for each fitness class the start date must be before the end date. A member may choose to participate in one or more fitness classes and may also choose one of the trainers as their personal trainer. Each fitness class is attended by one or more members and instructed by only one trainer. Not all trainers deliver fitness classes. After receiving the approval from an administrator, a member may choose to add multiple associate members who will have partial access to the services provided by the fitness centre, and an associate number (i.e., 1, 2, . . .) and the name of each associate member are recorded in the database. The database keeps track of equipment available in the fitness centre. Each piece of equipment has a unique ID and must have one of the following three status types: new, working or broken. Each technician has a mobile phone number. Technicians maintain equipment in the fitness centre and the database records the date of each maintenance event. Each piece of equipment should be maintained at least twice a year. Which of the following statements can be modelled by the ER diagram?",
    "choices": [
      "For each fitness class the start date must be before the end date.",
      "Each piece of equipment should be maintained at least twice a year.",
      "Each fitness class is instructed by only one trainer and not all trainers deliver fitness classes.",
      "Each piece of equipment has a unique ID and must have one of the following three status types: new, working or broken."
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Each fitness class is instructed by only one trainer and not all trainers deliver fitness classes."
  },
  "102": {
    "question_text": "Consider a database that stores names, addresses and unique IDs of employees in a fitness centre. The employees are classified into three categories: trainers, administrators and technicians. Each trainer has one or more specialities, e.g., weight gain, weight loss, strength building, etc. An administrator can register new members and be reached through a landline phone number. Each member is identified by an email address. The fitness centre organises fitness classes for members. Each class has a name, a start date, an end date, and a daily time slot. No two fitness classes have the same daily time slot, and for each fitness class the start date must be before the end date. A member may choose to participate in one or more fitness classes and may also choose one of the trainers as their personal trainer. Each fitness class is attended by one or more members and instructed by only one trainer. Not all trainers deliver fitness classes. After receiving the approval from an administrator, a member may choose to add multiple associate members who will have partial access to the services provided by the fitness centre, and an associate number (i.e., 1, 2, . . .) and the name of each associate member are recorded in the database. The database keeps track of equipment available in the fitness centre. Each piece of equipment has a unique ID and must have one of the following three status types: new, working or broken. Each technician has a mobile phone number. Technicians maintain equipment in the fitness centre and the database records the date of each maintenance event. Each piece of equipment should be maintained at least twice a year. If we model \"administrator\" as an entity type, which of the following is its key attribute?",
    "choices": [
      "Landline number",
      "Address",
      "ID",
      "Name"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "ID"
  },
  "101": {
    "question_text": "Consider a database that stores names, addresses and unique IDs of employees in a fitness centre. The employees are classified into three categories: trainers, administrators and technicians. Each trainer has one or more specialities, e.g., weight gain, weight loss, strength building, etc. An administrator can register new members and be reached through a landline phone number. Each member is identified by an email address. The fitness centre organises fitness classes for members. Each class has a name, a start date, an end date, and a daily time slot. No two fitness classes have the same daily time slot, and for each fitness class the start date must be before the end date. A member may choose to participate in one or more fitness classes and may also choose one of the trainers as their personal trainer. Each fitness class is attended by one or more members and instructed by only one trainer. Not all trainers deliver fitness classes. After receiving the approval from an administrator, a member may choose to add multiple associate members who will have partial access to the services provided by the fitness centre, and an associate number (i.e., 1, 2, . . .) and the name of each associate member are recorded in the database. The database keeps track of equipment available in the fitness centre. Each piece of equipment has a unique ID and must have one of the following three status types: new, working or broken. Each technician has a mobile phone number. Technicians maintain equipment in the fitness centre and the database records the date of each maintenance event. Each piece of equipment should be maintained at least twice a year. Each trainer has one or more specialities, e.g., weight gain, weight loss, strength building, etc. What is the best way to model the \"speciality\"of \"trainer\"?",
    "choices": [
      "Model \"trainer\" as an entity and model \"speciality\" as an attribute",
      "Model \"trainer\" as an entity and model \"speciality\" as a multi-valued attribute",
      "Model \"speciality\" as an entity type",
      "Model \"trainer\" as an entity type and model \"speciality\" as a weak entity type that is related to the entity type \"trainer\""
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Model \"trainer\" as an entity and model \"speciality\" as a multi-valued attribute"
  },
  "100": {
    "question_text": "Consider a database that stores names, addresses and unique IDs of employees in a fitness centre. The employees are classified into three categories: trainers, administrators and technicians. Each trainer has one or more specialities, e.g., weight gain, weight loss, strength building, etc. An administrator can register new members and be reached through a landline phone number. Each member is identified by an email address. The fitness centre organises fitness classes for members. Each class has a name, a start date, an end date, and a daily time slot. No two fitness classes have the same daily time slot, and for each fitness class the start date must be before the end date. A member may choose to participate in one or more fitness classes and may also choose one of the trainers as their personal trainer. Each fitness class is attended by one or more members and instructed by only one trainer. Not all trainers deliver fitness classes. After receiving the approval from an administrator, a member may choose to add multiple associate members who will have partial access to the services provided by the fitness centre, and an associate number (i.e., 1, 2, . . .) and the name of each associate member are recorded in the database. The database keeps track of equipment available in the fitness centre. Each piece of equipment has a unique ID and must have one of the following three status types: new, working or broken. Each technician has a mobile phone number. Technicians maintain equipment in the fitness centre and the database records the date of each maintenance event. Each piece of equipment should be maintained at least twice a year. Suppose that \"instruct\" is a relationship type between two entity types \"trainer\" and \"fitness class\". What is the participation constraint on \"fitness class\" in \"instruct\"?",
    "choices": [
      "Partial",
      "Total"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Total"
  },
  "99": {
    "question_text": "Consider a database that stores names, addresses and unique IDs of employees in a fitness centre. The employees are classified into three categories: trainers, administrators and technicians. Each trainer has one or more specialities, e.g., weight gain, weight loss, strength building, etc. An administrator can register new members and be reached through a landline phone number. Each member is identified by an email address. The fitness centre organises fitness classes for members. Each class has a name, a start date, an end date, and a daily time slot. No two fitness classes have the same daily time slot, and for each fitness class the start date must be before the end date. A member may choose to participate in one or more fitness classes and may also choose one of the trainers as their personal trainer. Each fitness class is attended by one or more members and instructed by only one trainer. Not all trainers deliver fitness classes. After receiving the approval from an administrator, a member may choose to add multiple associate members who will have partial access to the services provided by the fitness centre, and an associate number (i.e., 1, 2, . . .) and the name of each associate member are recorded in the database. The database keeps track of equipment available in the fitness centre. Each piece of equipment has a unique ID and must have one of the following three status types: new, working or broken. Each technician has a mobile phone number. Technicians maintain equipment in the fitness centre and the database records the date of each maintenance event. Each piece of equipment should be maintained at least twice a year. Suppose that \"instruct\" is a relationship type between two entity types \"trainer\" and \"fitness class\". What is the participation constraint on \"trainer\" in \"instruct\"?",
    "choices": [
      "Partial",
      "Total"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Partial"
  },
  "98": {
    "question_text": "Consider a database that stores names, addresses and unique IDs of employees in a fitness centre. The employees are classified into three categories: trainers, administrators and technicians. Each trainer has one or more specialities, e.g., weight gain, weight loss, strength building, etc. An administrator can register new members and be reached through a landline phone number. Each member is identified by an email address. The fitness centre organises fitness classes for members. Each class has a name, a start date, an end date, and a daily time slot. No two fitness classes have the same daily time slot, and for each fitness class the start date must be before the end date. A member may choose to participate in one or more fitness classes and may also choose one of the trainers as their personal trainer. Each fitness class is attended by one or more members and instructed by only one trainer. Not all trainers deliver fitness classes. After receiving the approval from an administrator, a member may choose to add multiple associate members who will have partial access to the services provided by the fitness centre, and an associate number (i.e., 1, 2, . . .) and the name of each associate member are recorded in the database. The database keeps track of equipment available in the fitness centre. Each piece of equipment has a unique ID and must have one of the following three status types: new, working or broken. Each technician has a mobile phone number. Technicians maintain equipment in the fitness centre and the database records the date of each maintenance event. Each piece of equipment should be maintained at least twice a year. What is the cardinality ratio of the relationship between \"trainer\" and \"fitness class\"?",
    "choices": [
      "1 : 1",
      "1: N",
      "N:N"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "1: N"
  },
  "97": {
    "question_text": "Consider a database that stores names, addresses and unique IDs of employees in a fitness centre. The employees are classified into three categories: trainers, administrators and technicians. Each trainer has one or more specialities, e.g., weight gain, weight loss, strength building, etc. An administrator can register new members and be reached through a landline phone number. Each member is identified by an email address. The fitness centre organises fitness classes for members. Each class has a name, a start date, an end date, and a daily time slot. No two fitness classes have the same daily time slot, and for each fitness class the start date must be before the end date. A member may choose to participate in one or more fitness classes and may also choose one of the trainers as their personal trainer. Each fitness class is attended by one or more members and instructed by only one trainer. Not all trainers deliver fitness classes. After receiving the approval from an administrator, a member may choose to add multiple associate members who will have partial access to the services provided by the fitness centre, and an associate number (i.e., 1, 2, . . .) and the name of each associate member are recorded in the database. The database keeps track of equipment available in the fitness centre. Each piece of equipment has a unique ID and must have one of the following three status types: new, working or broken. Each technician has a mobile phone number. Technicians maintain equipment in the fitness centre and the database records the date of each maintenance event. Each piece of equipment should be maintained at least twice a year. Suppose that \"participate\" is a relationship type between two entity types \"member\" and \"fitness class\". What is the participation constraint on \"fitness class\" in \"participate\"?",
    "choices": [
      "Partial",
      "Total"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Total"
  },
  "96": {
    "question_text": "Consider a database that stores names, addresses and unique IDs of employees in a fitness centre. The employees are classified into three categories: trainers, administrators and technicians. Each trainer has one or more specialities, e.g., weight gain, weight loss, strength building, etc. An administrator can register new members and be reached through a landline phone number. Each member is identified by an email address. The fitness centre organises fitness classes for members. Each class has a name, a start date, an end date, and a daily time slot. No two fitness classes have the same daily time slot, and for each fitness class the start date must be before the end date. A member may choose to participate in one or more fitness classes and may also choose one of the trainers as their personal trainer. Each fitness class is attended by one or more members and instructed by only one trainer. Not all trainers deliver fitness classes. After receiving the approval from an administrator, a member may choose to add multiple associate members who will have partial access to the services provided by the fitness centre, and an associate number (i.e., 1, 2, . . .) and the name of each associate member are recorded in the database. The database keeps track of equipment available in the fitness centre. Each piece of equipment has a unique ID and must have one of the following three status types: new, working or broken. Each technician has a mobile phone number. Technicians maintain equipment in the fitness centre and the database records the date of each maintenance event. Each piece of equipment should be maintained at least twice a year. Suppose that \"participate\" is a relationship type between two entity types \"member\" and \"fitness class\". What is the participation constraint on \"member\" in \"participate\"?",
    "choices": [
      "Partial",
      "Total"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Partial"
  },
  "95": {
    "question_text": "Consider a database that stores names, addresses and unique IDs of employees in a fitness centre. The employees are classified into three categories: trainers, administrators and technicians. Each trainer has one or more specialities, e.g., weight gain, weight loss, strength building, etc. An administrator can register new members and be reached through a landline phone number. Each member is identified by an email address. The fitness centre organises fitness classes for members. Each class has a name, a start date, an end date, and a daily time slot. No two fitness classes have the same daily time slot, and for each fitness class the start date must be before the end date. A member may choose to participate in one or more fitness classes and may also choose one of the trainers as their personal trainer. Each fitness class is attended by one or more members and instructed by only one trainer. Not all trainers deliver fitness classes. After receiving the approval from an administrator, a member may choose to add multiple associate members who will have partial access to the services provided by the fitness centre, and an associate number (i.e., 1, 2, . . .) and the name of each associate member are recorded in the database. The database keeps track of equipment available in the fitness centre. Each piece of equipment has a unique ID and must have one of the following three status types: new, working or broken. Each technician has a mobile phone number. Technicians maintain equipment in the fitness centre and the database records the date of each maintenance event. Each piece of equipment should be maintained at least twice a year. What is the cardinality ratio of the relationship between \"member\" and \"fitness class\"?",
    "choices": [
      "1 : 1",
      "1: N",
      "N:N  "
    ],
    "correct_answer": "N:N  "
  },
  "94": {
    "question_text": "Consider a database that stores names, addresses and unique IDs of employees in a fitness centre. The employees are classified into three categories: trainers, administrators and technicians. Each trainer has one or more specialities, e.g., weight gain, weight loss, strength building, etc. An administrator can register new members and be reached through a landline phone number. Each member is identified by an email address. The fitness centre organises fitness classes for members. Each class has a name, a start date, an end date, and a daily time slot. No two fitness classes have the same daily time slot, and for each fitness class the start date must be before the end date. A member may choose to participate in one or more fitness classes and may also choose one of the trainers as their personal trainer. Each fitness class is attended by one or more members and instructed by only one trainer. Not all trainers deliver fitness classes. After receiving the approval from an administrator, a member may choose to add multiple associate members who will have partial access to the services provided by the fitness centre, and an associate number (i.e., 1, 2, . . .) and the name of each associate member are recorded in the database. The database keeps track of equipment available in the fitness centre. Each piece of equipment has a unique ID and must have one of the following three status types: new, working or broken. Each technician has a mobile phone number. Technicians maintain equipment in the fitness centre and the database records the date of each maintenance event. Each piece of equipment should be maintained at least twice a year. Which of the following best models the relationship between \"employee\", and \"trainers\"/\"administrators\"/\"technicians\"?",
    "choices": [
      "Attribute and domain",
      "Entity and relationship",
      "Superclass and subclass",
      "Entity and attribute"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Superclass and subclass"
  },
  "93": {
    "question_text": "Consider a database that stores names, addresses and unique IDs of employees in a fitness centre. The employees are classified into three categories: trainers, administrators and technicians. Each trainer has one or more specialities, e.g., weight gain, weight loss, strength building, etc. An administrator can register new members and be reached through a landline phone number. Each member is identified by an email address. The fitness centre organises fitness classes for members. Each class has a name, a start date, an end date, and a daily time slot. No two fitness classes have the same daily time slot, and for each fitness class the start date must be before the end date. A member may choose to participate in one or more fitness classes and may also choose one of the trainers as their personal trainer. Each fitness class is attended by one or more members and instructed by only one trainer. Not all trainers deliver fitness classes. After receiving the approval from an administrator, a member may choose to add multiple associate members who will have partial access to the services provided by the fitness centre, and an associate number (i.e., 1, 2, . . .) and the name of each associate member are recorded in the database. The database keeps track of equipment available in the fitness centre. Each piece of equipment has a unique ID and must have one of the following three status types: new, working or broken. Each technician has a mobile phone number. Technicians maintain equipment in the fitness centre and the database records the date of each maintenance event. Each piece of equipment should be maintained at least twice a year. Which of the following can be modelled as a key attribute?",
    "choices": [
      "Phone number of technician",
      "Date of maintenance event",
      "Name of employee",
      "Time slot of fitness class"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Time slot of fitness class"
  },
  "92": {
    "question_text": "Consider a database that stores names, addresses and unique IDs of employees in a fitness centre. The employees are classified into three categories: trainers, administrators and technicians. Each trainer has one or more specialities, e.g., weight gain, weight loss, strength building, etc. An administrator can register new members and be reached through a landline phone number. Each member is identified by an email address. The fitness centre organises fitness classes for members. Each class has a name, a start date, an end date, and a daily time slot. No two fitness classes have the same daily time slot, and for each fitness class the start date must be before the end date. A member may choose to participate in one or more fitness classes and may also choose one of the trainers as their personal trainer. Each fitness class is attended by one or more members and instructed by only one trainer. Not all trainers deliver fitness classes. After receiving the approval from an administrator, a member may choose to add multiple associate members who will have partial access to the services provided by the fitness centre, and an associate number (i.e., 1, 2, . . .) and the name of each associate member are recorded in the database. The database keeps track of equipment available in the fitness centre. Each piece of equipment has a unique ID and must have one of the following three status types: new, working or broken. Each technician has a mobile phone number. Technicians maintain equipment in the fitness centre and the database records the date of each maintenance event. Each piece of equipment should be maintained at least twice a year. Which of the following can be modelled as a weak entity type?",
    "choices": [
      "Equipments' status",
      "Fitness class",
      "Associate member",
      "Trainers\u00e2\u0080\u0099 speciality"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Associate member"
  },
  "91": {
    "question_text": "Consider a database that stores names, addresses and unique IDs of employees in a fitness centre. The employees are classified into three categories: trainers, administrators and technicians. Each trainer has one or more specialities, e.g., weight gain, weight loss, strength building, etc. An administrator can register new members and be reached through a landline phone number. Each member is identified by an email address. The fitness centre organises fitness classes for members. Each class has a name, a start date, an end date, and a daily time slot. No two fitness classes have the same daily time slot, and for each fitness class the start date must be before the end date. A member may choose to participate in one or more fitness classes and may also choose one of the trainers as their personal trainer. Each fitness class is attended by one or more members and instructed by only one trainer. Not all trainers deliver fitness classes. After receiving the approval from an administrator, a member may choose to add multiple associate members who will have partial access to the services provided by the fitness centre, and an associate number (i.e., 1, 2, . . .) and the name of each associate member are recorded in the database. The database keeps track of equipment available in the fitness centre. Each piece of equipment has a unique ID and must have one of the following three status types: new, working or broken. Each technician has a mobile phone number. Technicians maintain equipment in the fitness centre and the database records the date of each maintenance event. Each piece of equipment should be maintained at least twice a year. Which of the following can be modelled as an attribute?",
    "choices": [
      "Weight gain",
      "Weight loss",
      "Strength building",
      "Speciality"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Speciality"
  },
  "90": {
    "question_text": "Consider a database that stores names, addresses and unique IDs of employees in a fitness centre. The employees are classified into three categories: trainers, administrators and technicians. Each trainer has one or more specialities, e.g., weight gain, weight loss, strength building, etc. An administrator can register new members and be reached through a landline phone number. Each member is identified by an email address. The fitness centre organises fitness classes for members. Each class has a name, a start date, an end date, and a daily time slot. No two fitness classes have the same daily time slot, and for each fitness class the start date must be before the end date. A member may choose to participate in one or more fitness classes and may also choose one of the trainers as their personal trainer. Each fitness class is attended by one or more members and instructed by only one trainer. Not all trainers deliver fitness classes. After receiving the approval from an administrator, a member may choose to add multiple associate members who will have partial access to the services provided by the fitness centre, and an associate number (i.e., 1, 2, . . .) and the name of each associate member are recorded in the database. The database keeps track of equipment available in the fitness centre. Each piece of equipment has a unique ID and must have one of the following three status types: new, working or broken. Each technician has a mobile phone number. Technicians maintain equipment in the fitness centre and the database records the date of each maintenance event. Each piece of equipment should be maintained at least twice a year. Which of the following can be modelled as an attribute?",
    "choices": [
      "Associate member",
      "Employee ID",
      "Fitness class",
      "Fitness centre"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Employee ID"
  },
  "89": {
    "question_text": "Consider a database that stores names, addresses and unique IDs of employees in a fitness centre. The employees are classified into three categories: trainers, administrators and technicians. Each trainer has one or more specialities, e.g., weight gain, weight loss, strength building, etc. An administrator can register new members and be reached through a landline phone number. Each member is identified by an email address. The fitness centre organises fitness classes for members. Each class has a name, a start date, an end date, and a daily time slot. No two fitness classes have the same daily time slot, and for each fitness class the start date must be before the end date. A member may choose to participate in one or more fitness classes and may also choose one of the trainers as their personal trainer. Each fitness class is attended by one or more members and instructed by only one trainer. Not all trainers deliver fitness classes. After receiving the approval from an administrator, a member may choose to add multiple associate members who will have partial access to the services provided by the fitness centre, and an associate number (i.e., 1, 2, . . .) and the name of each associate member are recorded in the database. The database keeps track of equipment available in the fitness centre. Each piece of equipment has a unique ID and must have one of the following three status types: new, working or broken. Each technician has a mobile phone number. Technicians maintain equipment in the fitness centre and the database records the date of each maintenance event. Each piece of equipment should be maintained at least twice a year. Which of the following can be modelled as an entity type?",
    "choices": [
      "Report of each maintenance event",
      "Status type of equipment",
      "Employee of fitness centre",
      "Time slot of fitness class"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Employee of fitness centre"
  },
  "88": {
    "question_text": "Consider a database that stores names, addresses and unique IDs of employees in a fitness centre. The employees are classified into three categories: trainers, administrators and technicians. Each trainer has one or more specialities, e.g., weight gain, weight loss, strength building, etc. An administrator can register new members and be reached through a landline phone number. Each member is identified by an email address. The fitness centre organises fitness classes for members. Each class has a name, a start date, an end date, and a daily time slot. No two fitness classes have the same daily time slot, and for each fitness class the start date must be before the end date. A member may choose to participate in one or more fitness classes and may also choose one of the trainers as their personal trainer. Each fitness class is attended by one or more members and instructed by only one trainer. Not all trainers deliver fitness classes. After receiving the approval from an administrator, a member may choose to add multiple associate members who will have partial access to the services provided by the fitness centre, and an associate number (i.e., 1, 2, . . .) and the name of each associate member are recorded in the database. The database keeps track of equipment available in the fitness centre. Each piece of equipment has a unique ID and must have one of the following three status types: new, working or broken. Each technician has a mobile phone number. Technicians maintain equipment in the fitness centre and the database records the date of each maintenance event. Each piece of equipment should be maintained at least twice a year. Which of the following can be modelled as an entity type?",
    "choices": [
      "Fitness centre",
      "Fitness class",
      "Trainers\u00e2\u0080\u0099 speciality",
      "Equipment ID"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Fitness class"
  },
  "87": {
    "question_text": "In ER diagram, weak entity is represented by a______________.",
    "choices": [
      "Diamond",
      "Rectangle",
      "Double diamond",
      "Double rectangle"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Double rectangle"
  },
  "86": {
    "question_text": "Which constraint can be captured by the ER diagram?",
    "choices": [
      "Primary key constraint",
      "Foreign key constraint",
      "Domain constraint"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Primary key constraint"
  },
  "15": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following Select statement correctly list the CourseNo and the corresponding number of students enrolled for all courses in 2019?",
    "choices": [
      "SELECT CourseNo, COUNT(*) AS NoOfStudents      FROM Enrol      WHERE Year = 2019      GROUP BY CourseNo;",
      "SELECT CourseNo, COUNT(*) AS NoOfStudents      FROM Student      WHERE Year = 2019      GROUP BY CourseNo;",
      "SELECT CourseNo, COUNT(*) AS NoOfStudents      FROM Student      WHERE Year = 2019      GROUP BY StudentID;",
      "SELECT CourseNo, COUNT(*) AS NoOfStudents      FROM Enrol   WHERE Year = 2019      GROUP BY StudentID;"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "SELECT CourseNo, COUNT(*) AS NoOfStudents      FROM Enrol      WHERE Year = 2019      GROUP BY CourseNo;"
  },
  "85": {
    "question_text": "How many rows, columns will be in the query result for the following Select statement? SELECT * FROM Course c WHERE NOT EXISTS (SELECT * FROM Enrol e WHERE c.CourseNo=e.CourseNo);",
    "choices": [
      "1,2",
      "3,3",
      "3,2",
      "1,3"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "1,2"
  },
  "9": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the query result for the following Select statement? SELECT * FROM Enrol e WHERE e.CourseNo IN (SELECT c.CourseNo FROM Course c WHERE CourseName = \u00e2\u0080\u0098Relational Databases\u00e2\u0080\u0099);",
    "choices": [
      "7",
      "3",
      "2",
      "1"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "2"
  },
  "84": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the query result for the following Select statement? SELECT * FROM Course c WHERE EXISTS (SELECT * FROM Enrol e WHERE c.CourseNo=e.CourseNo);",
    "choices": [
      "11",
      "7",
      "4",
      "3"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "3"
  },
  "83": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the query result for the following Select statement? SELECT * FROM Enrol e WHERE EXISTS (SELECT * FROM Course c WHERE c.CourseNo=e.CourseNo);",
    "choices": [
      "11",
      "8",
      "7",
      "4"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "7"
  },
  "82": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the query result for the following Select statement? SELECT * FROM Course, Enrol WHERE Course.CourseNo=Enrol.CourseNo AND Year = 2018;",
    "choices": [
      "12",
      "9",
      "7",
      "3"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "3"
  },
  "81": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the query result for the following Select statement? SELECT * FROM Course LEFT JOIN Enrol ON Course.CourseNo=Enrol.CourseNo;",
    "choices": [
      "13",
      "8",
      "4",
      "1"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "8"
  },
  "80": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the query result for the following Select statement? SELECT * FROM Course NATURAL JOIN Enrol;",
    "choices": [
      "28",
      "12",
      "7",
      "4"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "7"
  },
  "79": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the query result for the following Select statement? SELECT * FROM Course INNER JOIN Enrol ON Course.CourseNo=Enrol.CourseNo;",
    "choices": [
      "28",
      "12",
      "7",
      "4"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "7"
  },
  "78": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the query result for the following Select statement? SELECT * FROM Course, Enrol;",
    "choices": [
      "28",
      "12",
      "7",
      "4"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "28"
  },
  "77": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following Select statement? SELECT CourseNo FROM Study WHERE StudentID=102 EXCEPT SELECT CourseNo FROM Study WHERE StudentID=103;",
    "choices": [
      "4",
      "3",
      "2",
      "1"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "1"
  },
  "76": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following Select statement? SELECT StudentID FROM Study WHERE CourseNo='COMP2400' UNION SELECT StudentID FROM Study WHERE CourseNo='STAT2001';",
    "choices": [
      "6",
      "5",
      "4",
      "3"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "4"
  },
  "75": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following Select statement? SELECT CourseNo, COUNT(*) FROM Study GROUP BY CourseNo Having COUNT(*) > 1;",
    "choices": [
      "4",
      "3",
      "2",
      "1"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "2"
  },
  "74": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the query result for the following Select statement? SELECT StudentID, COUNT(*) FROM Study GROUP BY StudentID;",
    "choices": [
      "6",
      "4",
      "2",
      "1"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "4"
  },
  "73": {
    "question_text": "What is the query result for the following Select statement? SELECT COUNT(units), MIN(units) FROM Study;",
    "choices": [
      "4, 6",
      "3, 4",
      "6, 4",
      "4, 3"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "6, 4"
  },
  "72": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following Select statement? SELECT CourseNo FROM Study WHERE (StudentID = 102) OR (StudentID = 103);",
    "choices": [
      "4",
      "3",
      "2",
      "1"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "4"
  },
  "71": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the result for the following Select statement? SELECT DISTINCT CourseNo FROM Study;",
    "choices": [
      "4",
      "3",
      "2",
      "1"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "3"
  },
  "70": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the query result for the following Select statement? SELECT * FROM Study WHERE lower(Name) = 'tom';",
    "choices": [
      "3",
      "2",
      "1",
      "0"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "2"
  },
  "52": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the query result for the following Select statement? SELECT * FROM Study WHERE Name = 'Tom';",
    "choices": [
      "3",
      "2",
      "1",
      "0"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "1"
  },
  "69": {
    "question_text": "How many rows will be in the query result for the following Select statement? SELECT StudentID, Name FROM Study;",
    "choices": [
      "6",
      "4",
      "2",
      "0"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "6"
  },
  "68": {
    "question_text": "What referential integrity constraints do the following statements define? CREATE TABLE Student(StudentID INT PRIMARY KEY, Name VARCHAR(50)); CREATE TABLE Enrol (StudentID INT, CourseNo VARCHAR(20), Semester VARCHAR(50), FOREIGN KEY(StudentID) REFERENCES Student(StudentID));",
    "choices": [
      "StudentID cannot be null in Student",
      "StudentID cannot be null in Enrol",
      "Every StudentID appearing in Enrol must exist in Student",
      "Every  StudentID appearing in Student must exist in Enrol"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Every StudentID appearing in Enrol must exist in Student"
  },
  "67": {
    "question_text": "If {StudentID, CourseNo, Semester} is the primary key for the relation schema Enrol, then the entity integrity constraints guarantee ___________.",
    "choices": [
      "At least one of the attributes in the primary key is not null",
      "None of the attributes in the primary key can be null",
      "All the attributes in the primary key can be null"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "None of the attributes in the primary key can be null"
  },
  "66": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following statement correctly creates the relation schema Enrol(StudentID: INT, CourseNo: STRING, Semester: STRING)?",
    "choices": [
      "CREATE TABLE Enrol(StudentID INT; CourseNo VARCHAR(20); Semester VARCHAR(50)),",
      "CREATE TABLE Enrol(StudentID INT, CourseNo VARCHAR(20), Semester VARCHAR(50)),",
      "CREATE TABLE Enrol(StudentID INT, CourseNo VARCHAR(20), Semester VARCHAR(50));"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "CREATE TABLE Enrol(StudentID INT, CourseNo VARCHAR(20), Semester VARCHAR(50));"
  },
  "65": {
    "question_text": "What will be the output of the following query? SELECT COUNT(*) FROM person;",
    "choices": [
      "Show all rows and columns of table \u00e2\u0080\u009cperson\u00e2\u0080\u009d",
      "Show the number of rows of table \u00e2\u0080\u009cperson\u00e2\u0080\u009d",
      "Show the number of columns of table \u00e2\u0080\u009cperson\u00e2\u0080\u009d"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Show the number of rows of table \u00e2\u0080\u009cperson\u00e2\u0080\u009d"
  },
  "64": {
    "question_text": "What will be the output of the following query? SELECT * FROM person;",
    "choices": [
      "Show all rows and columns of table \u00e2\u0080\u009cperson\u00e2\u0080\u009d",
      "Show the number of rows of table \u00e2\u0080\u009cperson\u00e2\u0080\u009d",
      "Show the number of columns of table \u00e2\u0080\u009cperson\u00e2\u0080\u009d"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Show all rows and columns of table \u00e2\u0080\u009cperson\u00e2\u0080\u009d"
  },
  "17": {
    "question_text": "The _____ operation combines two relations by merging pairs of matching tuples, one from each relation, into a single tuple.",
    "choices": [
      "Select",
      "Join",
      "Union"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Join"
  },
  "16": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following commands do we use to delete all the tuples from a relation (R)?",
    "choices": [
      "delete table R",
      "drop table R",
      "delete from R",
      "drop from R"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "delete from R"
  },
  "63": {
    "question_text": "What is the syntax to add a new tuple to a relation? (Consider D as the relation and (a, b, c) as the new tuple)",
    "choices": [
      "enter into D (a, b, c);",
      "insert into D values (a, b, c);",
      "insert into D (a, b, c);",
      "insert (a, b, c) values into D;"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "insert into D values (a, b, c);"
  },
  "7": {
    "question_text": "In SQL, which command is used to add new rows to a table?",
    "choices": [
      "Alter Table",
      "Add row",
      "Insert",
      "Append"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Insert"
  },
  "6": {
    "question_text": "In SQL, which of the following is included in DML (Data Manipulation Language)?",
    "choices": [
      "Create",
      "Alter Table",
      "Drop Table",
      "Update"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Update"
  },
  "5": {
    "question_text": "The ________ clause is used to list the attributes desired in the result of a query.",
    "choices": [
      "Select",
      "Update",
      "Delete",
      "Create"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Select"
  },
  "62": {
    "question_text": "The basic data type char(n) is a _____-length character string and varchar(n) is _____-length character string.",
    "choices": [
      "Fixed, Fixed",
      "Variable, Variable",
      "Fixed, Variable",
      "Variable, Fixed"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Fixed, Variable"
  },
  "61": {
    "question_text": "The command \u00e2\u0080\u009cCREATE TABLE\u00e2\u0080\u009d belongs to ________.",
    "choices": [
      "DML",
      "DDL",
      "DCL",
      "TCL"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "DDL"
  },
  "60": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following commands can be used to remove attribute A from a relation R?",
    "choices": [
      "Alter table R delete A",
      "Alter table R drop column A",
      "Alter table drop A from R",
      "Delete A from R"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Alter table R drop column A"
  },
  "59": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following commands is used to remove relation schema R from a database?",
    "choices": [
      "Drop table R",
      "Drop relation R",
      "Delete table R",
      "Delete from R"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Drop table R"
  },
  "58": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following commands is used to create a new relation in PostgreSQL?",
    "choices": [
      "create table(\u00e2\u0080\u00a6)",
      "create relation(\u00e2\u0080\u00a6)",
      "New table(\u00e2\u0080\u00a6)",
      "New relation(\u00e2\u0080\u00a6)"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "create table(\u00e2\u0080\u00a6)"
  },
  "57": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following data types is not supported in PostgreSQL?",
    "choices": [
      "Char(n)",
      "String(n)",
      "Varchar(n)",
      "Bit(n)"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "String(n)"
  },
  "56": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following is true?",
    "choices": [
      "A superkey is always a candidate key",
      "A candidate key is always a superkey",
      "A superkey is always a primary key",
      "A candidate key is always a primary key"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "A candidate key is always a superkey"
  },
  "55": {
    "question_text": "If {a} is a superkey key in R(a,b,c), then_______________.",
    "choices": [
      "{a,b} must not be a superkey",
      "{a,c} must be a candidate key",
      "{a} must be a candidate key"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "{a} must be a candidate key"
  },
  "54": {
    "question_text": "If {a,b} is a candidate key in R(a,b,c), then___________.",
    "choices": [
      "{a,b,c} must be a candidate key",
      "{a,b,c} must be a superkey",
      "{a} must be a superkey"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "{a,b,c} must be a superkey"
  },
  "53": {
    "question_text": "If {a,b} is a superkey in R(a,b,c), then",
    "choices": [
      "{a,b,c} must be a superkey",
      "{a,b,c} must not be a superkey"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "{a,b,c} must be a superkey"
  },
  "51": {
    "question_text": "If {a,b} is a superkey in R(a,b,c), then________________.",
    "choices": [
      "{a,b,c} must not be a superkey",
      "{a,b,c} must not be a candidate key",
      "{a,b,c} must be a primary key"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "{a,b,c} must not be a candidate key"
  },
  "50": {
    "question_text": "If a relation has a foreign key, then it is called a ______ relation of the foreign key dependency.",
    "choices": [
      "Referenced",
      "Referencing"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Referencing"
  },
  "49": {
    "question_text": "Choose the correct statement regarding superkeys",
    "choices": [
      "A superkey is an attribute or a set of attributes that can uniquely identify a tuple in a relation",
      "A superkey is a tuple or a set of multiple tuples that can uniquely identify an attribute in a relation",
      "Every superkey is a candidate key",
      "A superkey is an attribute or a set of attributes that distinguish the relation from other relations"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "A superkey is an attribute or a set of attributes that can uniquely identify a tuple in a relation"
  },
  "48": {
    "question_text": "In the relational data model, a _________ is used to enforce referential integrity between two tables.",
    "choices": [
      "Candidate key",
      "Foreign key",
      "Superkey",
      "Primary key"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Foreign key"
  },
  "47": {
    "question_text": "Which one of the following is a set of one or more attributes taken collectively to uniquely identify a tuple?",
    "choices": [
      "Domain",
      "Subkey",
      "Superkey",
      "Foreign key"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Superkey"
  },
  "46": {
    "question_text": "The order of tuples in a relation is ____. The order of attributes in a relation is _________.",
    "choices": [
      "Important; Important",
      "Important; Not important",
      "Not important; Important",
      "Not important; Not important"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Not important; Important"
  },
  "45": {
    "question_text": "Consider a relation schema Course(courseID,courseName,semester). Here the courseID, courseName and semester are __________.",
    "choices": [
      "Relations",
      "Attributes",
      "Tuples",
      "Instances"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Attributes"
  },
  "14": {
    "question_text": "The term _______ is used to refer to a row in the relational data model.",
    "choices": [
      "Attribute",
      "Tuple",
      "Field",
      "Instance"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Tuple"
  },
  "13": {
    "question_text": "An attribute is a __________ in a table in the relational data model.",
    "choices": [
      "Row",
      "Column",
      "Value",
      "Tuple"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Column"
  },
  "1": {
    "question_text": "_________ is the sets of all possible values for an attribute.",
    "choices": [
      "Table",
      "Tuple",
      "Attribute",
      "Domain"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Domain"
  },
  "0": {
    "question_text": "In the relational data model, a table is considered as____________.",
    "choices": [
      "Range",
      "Domain",
      "Relation",
      "Tuple"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Relation"
  },
  "44": {
    "question_text": "If A = {1,2}, B = {a,b}, C = {1,2,3}, and D = {a,b,c}, then A x B \u00e2\u008a\u0086 C x D=_________.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "True"
  },
  "43": {
    "question_text": "If A = {1,2}, B = {a,b}, C = {1,2,3}, and D = {a,b,c}, then A x A \u00e2\u008a\u0086 A x C =__________.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "True"
  },
  "42": {
    "question_text": "If A = {1,2}, B = {a,b}, C = {1,2,3}, and D = {a,b,c}, then (A x A) \u00e2\u008a\u0086 (C x C) =____________.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "True"
  },
  "41": {
    "question_text": "If A = {1,2}, B = {a,b}, C = {1,2,3}, and D = {a,b,c}, then B \u00e2\u008a\u0086 B x B =_________.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "False"
  },
  "40": {
    "question_text": "If A = {1,2}, B = {a,b}, C = {1,2,3}, and D = {a,b,c}, then A \u00e2\u008a\u0086 A x B=__________.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "False"
  },
  "39": {
    "question_text": "If A = {1,2}, B = {a,b}, C = {1,2,3}, and D = {a,b,c}, then (C x D) \u00e2\u0080\u0093 (A x B) = _________.",
    "choices": [
      "{(1,c) ,(2,c),(3,a),(3,b),(3,c)}",
      "{(1,a), (1,b) , (2,a) , (2,b)}",
      "{(1,a),(1,b),(1,c),(2,a),(2,b),(2,c)}"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "{(1,c) ,(2,c),(3,a),(3,b),(3,c)}"
  },
  "38": {
    "question_text": "The cardinality of a set, |X|, is the number of elements of the set X. If |A| = 10, |B| = 5, and |A \u00e2\u0088\u00a9 B| = 2, then |A U B|=__________.",
    "choices": [
      "11",
      "12",
      "13",
      "14"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "13"
  },
  "37": {
    "question_text": "The cardinality of a set, |X|, is the number of elements of the set X. If |A| = 3 and |B| = 2. then |A x B| =__________.",
    "choices": [
      "5",
      "6",
      "12",
      "24"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "6"
  },
  "36": {
    "question_text": "The shaded area of the figure is best described by",
    "choices": [
      "A U C  \u00e2\u0080\u0093  B",
      "B \u00e2\u0080\u0093 A \u00e2\u0080\u0093 C",
      "(A \u00e2\u0088\u00a9 C) \u00e2\u0088\u00a9 B",
      "(AUC) \u00e2\u0080\u0093 (B \u00e2\u0088\u00a9 A) \u00e2\u0080\u0093 (B \u00e2\u0088\u00a9C)"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "B \u00e2\u0080\u0093 A \u00e2\u0080\u0093 C"
  },
  "35": {
    "question_text": "The shaded area of the figure is best described by",
    "choices": [
      "A U B",
      "(A U B) \u00e2\u0080\u0093 (A \u00e2\u0088\u00a9 B)",
      "A \u00e2\u0080\u0093 B",
      "A \u00e2\u0088\u00a9 B"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "(A U B) \u00e2\u0080\u0093 (A \u00e2\u0088\u00a9 B)"
  },
  "34": {
    "question_text": "The shaded area of the figure is best described by",
    "choices": [
      "A",
      "(A U B) -B",
      "A \u00e2\u0088\u00a9 B",
      "B- (A \u00e2\u0088\u00a9 B)"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "(A U B) -B"
  },
  "33": {
    "question_text": "The shaded area of the figure is best described by _________",
    "choices": [
      "A \u00e2\u0088\u00a9 B",
      "A U B",
      "A",
      "B"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "A \u00e2\u0088\u00a9 B"
  },
  "32": {
    "question_text": "In which of the following set definitions is A - B equal to B \u00e2\u0080\u0093 A?",
    "choices": [
      "A = {1, 2, 3}, B = {2, 3, 4}",
      "A = {1, 2, 3}, B = {1, 2, 3, 4}",
      "A = {1, 2, 3}, B = {2, 3, 1}",
      "A = {1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6}, B = {2, 3, 4, 5, 1}"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "A = {1, 2, 3}, B = {2, 3, 1}"
  },
  "31": {
    "question_text": "If A = {1, 2, 3} and A \u00e2\u0088\u00a9 B = {2, 3}, then the number of elements in B cannot be________.",
    "choices": [
      "1",
      "2",
      "3",
      "4"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "1"
  },
  "30": {
    "question_text": "If S = {1,2} and T = {1,2,3}, then (S x T) - (S x S) is________.",
    "choices": [
      "{(1,1), (2,2)}",
      "{(1,1), (1,2), (1,3)}",
      "{(1,3), (2,3)}"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "{(1,3), (2,3)}"
  },
  "29": {
    "question_text": "If S = {1,2} and T = {1,2,3}, then S x (T - S) =____________.",
    "choices": [
      "{1, 2, 3}",
      "{(1,1), (1,2), (1,3)}",
      "{(1,3), (2,3)}"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "{(1,3), (2,3)}"
  },
  "28": {
    "question_text": "If S = {1,2} and T = {1,2,3}, then S x S =_______.",
    "choices": [
      "{1, 2, 3}",
      "{(1,1), (1,2), (2,1), (2,2)}",
      "{1, 2}"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "{(1,1), (1,2), (2,1), (2,2)}"
  },
  "27": {
    "question_text": "Let A = {1, 2, 3} and B = {1, 2, 5}, then (A - B) \u00e2\u0088\u00aa (B - A)= _______.",
    "choices": [
      "{1,2,3,5}",
      "{1,2}",
      "{3,5}",
      "{1,2,3}"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "{3,5}"
  },
  "26": {
    "question_text": "Set A, B, and C are defined as follows: A = {2,3,4,5,6,7, 8, 9}, B = {3,5,7}, C = {3,5,7,9}. Select true or false for the following statement. B \u00e2\u008a\u0084 (A \u00e2\u0088\u00a9 C)=____________.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "False"
  },
  "25": {
    "question_text": "Set A, B, and C are defined as follows: A = {2,3,4,5,6,7, 8, 9}, B = {3,5,7}, C = {3,5,7,9}. Select true or false for the following statement. B \u00e2\u008a\u0082 (A \u00e2\u0088\u00aa B)=_________.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "True"
  },
  "24": {
    "question_text": "Set A, B, and C are defined as follows: A = {2,3,4,5,6,7, 8, 9}, B = {3,5,7}, C = {3,5,7,9}. Select true or false for the following statement. (A \u00e2\u0088\u00aa C) \u00e2\u008a\u0082 B =__________.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "False"
  },
  "23": {
    "question_text": "If A and B are two sets, and A \u00c3\u0097 B consists of 6 elements: If three elements of A \u00c3\u0097 B are (2, 5) (3, 7) (4, 7) then A \u00c3\u0097 B=____.",
    "choices": [
      "{(2, 2), (7, 7), (5, 5), (3, 3), (4, 4),(4,7)}",
      "{(2, 5), (2, 7), (3, 5), (3, 7), (3,4), (4,3)}",
      "{(2, 5), (2, 7), (3, 5), (3, 7), (4,5), (4,7)}",
      "{(2, 5), (3, 7), (5, 5), (4, 7), (2,7), (3,5)}"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "{(2, 5), (2, 7), (3, 5), (3, 7), (4,5), (4,7)}"
  },
  "22": {
    "question_text": "If A = {2, 3, 4, 5}, B = {4, 5, 6, 7}, C = {6, 7, 8, 9}, D = {8, 9, 10, 11}, then (A - D) \u00e2\u0088\u00a9 (B - C)=__________.",
    "choices": [
      "{6,7}",
      "{2,3}",
      "{4,5}",
      "{8,9}"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "{4,5}"
  },
  "21": {
    "question_text": "If A = {2, 3, 4, 5}, B = {4, 5, 6, 7}, C = {6, 7, 8, 9}, D = {8, 9, 10, 11}, then (A \u00e2\u0088\u00aa B) \u00e2\u0088\u00a9 C=___________.",
    "choices": [
      "{2, 3, 4}",
      "{6, 7}",
      "{2, 3, 8, 9}",
      "{4, 5}"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "{6, 7}"
  },
  "20": {
    "question_text": "If A = {2, 3, 4, 5}, B = {4, 5, 6, 7}, C = {6, 7, 8, 9}, D = {8, 9, 10, 11}, then (A \u00e2\u0088\u00aa B) \u00e2\u0088\u00aa C=_________.",
    "choices": [
      "{2, 4, 5, 9, 10, 11, 8}",
      "{2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9}",
      "{1, 4, 9, 7,8,11,10}",
      "{4, 5,7,8,9,10,11}"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "{2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9}"
  },
  "11": {
    "question_text": "If A = {2, 3, 4, 5}, B = {4, 5, 6, 7}, C = {6, 7, 8, 9}, D = {8, 9, 10, 11}, then A - (A \u00e2\u0088\u00a9 B)=________.",
    "choices": [
      "{2,3}",
      "{6,7}",
      "{2,3,4,5}",
      "{4,5,6,7}"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "{2,3}"
  },
  "19": {
    "question_text": "If A = {2, 3, 4, 5}, B = {4, 5, 6, 7}, C = {6, 7, 8, 9}, D = {8, 9, 10, 11}, then A - B=___________.",
    "choices": [
      "{2,3}",
      "{6,7}",
      "{2,3,4,5}",
      "{4,5,6,7}"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "{2,3}"
  },
  "10": {
    "question_text": "If A \u00c3\u0097 B = {(p, x), (p, y), (q, x), (q, y)}, then A = _____and B = ______.",
    "choices": [
      "A = {p, q} and B = {x, y}",
      "A = {p, q, x} and B = { y}",
      "A = {p} and B = {q, x, y}",
      "A ={x, y} and B = {p, q}"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "A = {p, q} and B = {x, y}"
  },
  "8": {
    "question_text": "Which of the following two sets are equal?",
    "choices": [
      "A = {1, 2} and B = {1}",
      "A = {1, 2} and B = {1, 2, 3}",
      "A = {1, 2, 3} and B = {2, 1, 3}",
      "A = {1, 2, 4} and B = {1, 2, 3}"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "A = {1, 2, 3} and B = {2, 1, 3}"
  },
  "18": {
    "question_text": "The cardinality of a set is the number of elements of the set. What is the cardinality of the set of odd positive integers less than 10?",
    "choices": [
      "10",
      "5",
      "3",
      "20"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "5"
  },
  "3": {
    "question_text": "The Cartesian product B x A is always equal to the Cartesian product A x B. Is it true or false?",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "False"
  },
  "12": {
    "question_text": "What is the Cartesian product of A = {1, 2} and B = {a, b}?",
    "choices": [
      "{(1, a), (1, b), (2, a), (b, b)}",
      "{(1, 1), (2, 2), (a, a), (b, b)}",
      "{(1, a), (2, a), (1, b), (2, b)}",
      "{(a, 1), (a, 2), (b, 1), (b, 2)}"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "{(1, a), (2, a), (1, b), (2, b)}"
  },
  "4": {
    "question_text": "The set that consists of all odd positive integers less than 10 is represented by _____________.",
    "choices": [
      "{1, 2, 3}",
      "{1, 3, 5, 7, 9}",
      "{1, 2, 5, 9}",
      "{1, 5, 7, 9, 11}"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "{1, 3, 5, 7, 9}"
  },
  "2": {
    "question_text": "A __________ is a collection of distinct elements.",
    "choices": [
      "Relation",
      "Function",
      "Set",
      "Tuple"
    ],
    "correct_answer": "Set"
  }
}